Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节初级课程。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to talk about winter but specifically about the clothes you wear during winter when
我们要聊聊冬天，但具体来说是冬天穿的衣服，当外面
it's very, very cold outside.
非常非常冷的时候。
That's right and I hear you're not too familiar with some of these practices because where
没错，我听说你对这些做法不太熟悉，因为你来自的地方
you come from you don't really have winter.
其实没有冬天。
We don't have winter.
我们没有冬天。
We have dry season and rainy season but same temperature.
我们有旱季和雨季，但温度差不多。
Well Chicago definitely has a snowy season so I'm very familiar with these things.
嗯，芝加哥绝对有雪季，所以我对这些很熟悉。
So let's jump right into today's dialogue.
那我们直接进入今天的对话吧。
We'll be hearing it one time and in a minute we'll be back to talk about it.
我们会先听一遍，然后稍后再回来讨论。
Bye mom.
再见，妈妈。
Wait, Jimmy.
等等，Jimmy。
It's cold outside.
外面很冷。
Put a hat on.
戴上帽子。
Okay, bye.
好的，再见。
No, wait.
不，等等。
You'll be too cold without mittens.
不戴手套你会太冷的。
All right, see ya.
好吧，回头见。
Hold on.
等一下。
With that wind you're going to catch a cold.
刮着风，你会感冒的。
Wear this scarf.
戴上这条围巾。
Okay, see you after school.
好的，放学后见。
Oh, and earmuffs.
哦，还有耳罩。
Put these on.
戴上这个。
Here we go.
好了。
Mom?
妈妈？
Yes, honey?
怎么了，亲爱的？
I can't breathe.
我喘不过气了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So there were a couple of different items of clothing that we saw in this dialogue.
所以这个对话里出现了几件不同的衣物。
So let's look at them now in Language Takeaway.
那我们现在在“语言要点”环节来看看它们。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, well, first of all we have mom and Jimmy.
好的，首先我们有妈妈和Jimmy。
Jimmy is a boy's name.
Jimmy是个男孩的名字。
He's a little boy.
他是个小男孩。
And mom is saying goodbye to him, but first she wants him to put on clothes.
妈妈在跟他告别，但首先她想让他穿上衣服。
So the first item, the first thing she asks him to put on is a hat.
所以第一件物品，她让他戴上的第一样东西是帽子。
A hat.
帽子。
Now you probably have seen like a baseball cap or many different types of hats.
你可能见过棒球帽或各种不同类型的帽子。
And sometimes in other languages they have specific names for a hat for winter, right?
有时候在其他语言里，冬天戴的帽子有特定的名称，对吧？
But in English it's a hat.
但在英语里就是帽子。
Anything that covers your head is a hat.
任何盖住头的东西都叫帽子。
That's kind of like the category.
这有点像一个大类。
So maybe this one is a warm wool hat, but in the end it's a hat.
所以这个可能是一顶保暖的羊毛帽，但归根结底还是帽子。
It's a hat.
就是帽子。
Okay.
好的。
So he's put on the hat.
所以他戴上了帽子。
Now what else is he going to put on?
那他还要穿什么呢？
Well, we need to keep our fingers warm.
嗯，我们需要让手指保暖。
So there are two kinds of ways to keep your fingers warm.
有两种方法可以让手指保暖。
And the way in this dialogue that the boy keeps his fingers warm is with mittens.
在这个对话里，男孩让手指保暖的方式是戴连指手套。
All right, so mittens you put on your hands.
好的，连指手套是戴在手上的。
Now what's the difference between mittens and gloves?
那连指手套和分指手套有什么区别呢？
Okay, gloves have special places for each finger.
好的，分指手套每个手指都有单独的位置。
One, two, three, four, five on each hand.
每只手有五个手指，一个、两个、三个、四个、五个。
And mittens, there's two spaces, one for your thumb and one for all your other fingers.
而连指手套有两个空间，一个给大拇指，另一个给其他所有手指。
So that means you can't really hold things.
所以这意味着你不太能拿东西。
So you kind of look like a penguin or something like that.
所以你看起来有点像企鹅之类的。
Yeah, you look like a, yeah, exactly like a penguin.
是啊，看起来就像，对，就像企鹅。
And it's mostly for children.
而且这主要是给小孩用的。
Adults don't wear mittens because adults need to hold things like keys and phones and car
大人不戴连指手套，因为大人需要拿东西，比如钥匙、手机和汽车
steering wheels.
方向盘。
So in this case, mittens is usually for children.
所以在这种情况下，连指手套通常是给小孩的。
Okay, so mittens.
好的，所以是连指手套。
And well, the mother is still a little bit worried.
嗯，妈妈还是有点担心。
So she tells him to wear a scarf.
所以她让他戴上围巾。
Okay, a scarf is a long, usually made of wool, a long piece of fabric that you put around
好的，围巾是一条长长的，通常由羊毛制成，一块长条布料，你把它围在
your neck to keep your neck warm.
脖子上，让脖子保暖。
Okay, so a scarf.
好的，所以是围巾。
A scarf.
围巾。
Okay, and he's put on the mittens, the scarf, the hat, and he's missing some earmuffs.
好的，他戴上了连指手套、围巾、帽子，还缺个耳罩。
Okay, this is a little funny because usually if you're wearing a hat, you don't need earmuffs.
好的，这有点好笑，因为通常如果你戴了帽子，就不需要耳罩了。
But earmuffs are like headphones, but they keep your ears warm.
但耳罩像耳机一样，但它们能让耳朵保暖。
And we wear these, they don't cover your head, they just cover your ears.
我们戴这个，它们不盖住头，只盖住耳朵。
And usually they're just two round circles over your ears.
通常就是两个圆形的圈盖在耳朵上。
So as you say, exactly, they look like big earphones and they keep your ears warm.
所以就像你说的，没错，它们看起来像大耳机，能让耳朵保暖。
Now, as you say, you usually don't wear this if you're wearing a hat because, well, you
现在，就像你说的，如果你戴了帽子，通常不会戴这个，因为，嗯，你
would put your ears inside your hat, right?
会把耳朵塞进帽子里，对吧？
So it looks pretty silly if he's wearing all of this together.
所以如果他所有这些都一起戴上，看起来挺傻的。
All right.
好的。
And so those four key items, those four key pieces of clothing are for our language takeaway
所以这四个关键物品，这四件关键衣物就是我们今天“语言要点”
today.
的内容。
Why don't we listen to this dialogue again, and we'll come back soon to talk about Fluency
我们为什么不把这段对话再听一遍呢？我们很快会回来讨论“流利度
Builder.
构建”。
Bye, mom.
再见，妈妈。
Wait, Jimmy, it's cold outside.
等等，Jimmy，外面很冷。
Put a hat on.
戴上帽子。
Okay, bye.
好的，再见。
No, wait, you'll be too cold without mittens.
不，等等，不戴连指手套你会太冷的。
All right, see ya.
好吧，回头见。
Hold on, with that wind you're gonna catch a cold.
等一下，刮着风，你会感冒的。
Wear this scarf.
戴上这条围巾。
Okay, see you after school.
好的，放学后见。
Oh, and earmuffs, put these on.
哦，还有耳罩，戴上这个。
Here we go.
好了。
Mom?
妈妈？
Yes, honey?
怎么了，亲爱的？
I can't breathe.
我喘不过气了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at four key phrases on Fluency Builder.
那现在我们来看看“流利度构建”里的四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay, this first phrase, as I said before, has to do with the mom and the boy saying
好的，第一个短语，就像我之前说的，跟妈妈和男孩互相
goodbye to each other.
告别有关。
So he says, all right, see ya.
所以他说，好吧，回头见。
See ya.
回头见。
Ya.
见。
Okay, so see as in to look, to, right?
好的，所以“see”是看的意思，对吧？
You see something.
你看东西。
And what about Y-A-Y?
那Y-A-Y呢？
Ya.
见。
Okay, so this is a very spoken language way of saying you.
好的，这是一种非常口语化的说法，表示“你”。
So we could say, see you later, but if you want to make it shorter, you can say, see
所以我们可以说“see you later”，但如果你想缩短，可以说“see
ya.
ya”。
See ya.
回头见。
Bye.
拜拜。
Bye, goodbye.
拜拜，再见。
All right, so see ya.
好的，所以是“回头见”。
And then what's our next way of saying goodbye?
那我们下一个说再见的方式是什么？
Hold on.
等一下。
Oh, wait, that's...
哦，等等，那是……
We're not there yet.
我们还没到那一步。
No, hold on is our next phrase and this is a way to say wait.
不，“hold on”是我们的下一个短语，这是一种说“等等”的方式。
Wait, hold on.
等等，等一下。
So you just say hold on, it means wait.
所以你只要说“hold on”，它的意思就是“等等”。
It's not really rude, right?
这不算很粗鲁，对吧？
It's just a little bit more casual.
只是稍微随意一点。
Exactly.
没错。
It's very casual.
非常随意。
So you cannot say hold.
所以你不能只说“hold”。
That doesn't make sense.
那说不通。
You have to use these two words together.
你必须把这两个词一起用。
Hold on.
等一下。
So like I said before with Marco who wants to go fast, I could say, hold on.
就像我之前跟想走快的Marco说的，我可以说“hold on”。
Wait a second.
等一下。
All right.
好的。
Okay, so hold on.
好的，所以“hold on”。
See ya.
再见。
And now you got to be careful because you're going to catch a cold.
现在你得小心了，因为你会感冒的。
To catch a cold.
感冒。
Okay, so a cold is when you cough, you have a sore throat, it's starting to get cold outside
好的，感冒就是你咳嗽、喉咙痛，外面开始变冷，
and you don't feel well.
而且你感觉不舒服。
So you have a runny nose.
所以你流鼻涕。
It's an illness.
这是一种病。
And most people get this every year.
大多数人每年都会得一次。
It's very common.
这很常见。
But you don't get a cold, you catch a cold.
但你不是“得到”感冒，你是“染上”感冒。
So catch is the same word we use for when we talk about sports like throwing and catching.
所以“catch”这个词和我们谈论运动时用的“扔和接”是同一个词。
It's almost like it just hits you.
就好像它突然击中了你。
It's so fast.
它来得太快了。
You just catch a cold.
你只是染上了感冒。
So that's really important what you just said because you don't use the verb get.
你刚才说的这点很重要，因为你不用动词“get”。
You don't get a cold.
你不是“得到”感冒。
You catch a cold.
你是“染上”感冒。
Or if you say that you were sick last week because you had a cold, you would say, oh,
或者如果你说你上周因为感冒生病了，你会说，哦，
I caught a cold or I had a cold.
我染上了感冒，或者我得了感冒。
Exactly.
没错。
So remember present tense, I catch a cold.
所以记住现在时：我染上感冒。
Past tense, I caught a cold last week.
过去时：我上周染上了感冒。
Okay.
好的。
And our last phrase for fluency builder is here we go.
我们流利度提升的最后一个短语是“here we go”。
Here we go.
开始吧。
Okay, so when do we hear this phrase?
好的，那我们什么时候听到这个短语？
So the mother says to the boy, put these on, here we go.
所以妈妈对男孩说：“戴上这些，好了。”
So she's doing something with him.
所以她正在帮他做点什么。
She's helping him put his earmuffs on.
她在帮他戴上耳罩。
And here we go is a way to say, okay, I've finished.
而“here we go”是一种说“好了，我完成了”的方式。
Okay, I'm done.
好的，我弄好了。
Okay, your earmuffs are on you.
好的，你的耳罩戴好了。
So you're ready.
所以你准备好了。
Here you go.
给你。
Right.
对。
So we say here we go.
所以我们说“here we go”。
Like everything is ready.
就像一切都准备好了。
Your earmuffs are on.
你的耳罩戴上了。
Exactly.
没错。
So maybe I'm on my computer and I have a problem and I'm waiting, waiting, waiting, waiting,
所以也许我在用电脑，遇到了问题，我在等啊等啊等啊等，
waiting.
等啊等。
And you know when the bar's loading.
你知道当进度条在加载的时候。
And finally, ding, it's ready.
最后，叮的一声，它准备好了。
Here we go.
好了。
It's ready.
准备好了。
Now I can start.
现在我可以开始了。
It's ready.
准备好了。
Or sometimes a waitress will come and serve you food and say, here we go.
或者有时候女服务员会过来给你上菜，然后说：“来了。”
Here's your order.
这是你的订单。
Exactly.
没错。
So this is a way to say what you've been waiting for.
所以这是一种说“你一直在等的东西”的方式。
It's ready now.
现在准备好了。
Okay.
好的。
Great.
太好了。
So I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue one last time before we come
所以我觉得是时候让我们最后听一遍这段对话，然后再回来。
back.
回来。
Here we go.
开始吧。
Bye mom.
再见，妈妈。
Wait, Jimmy.
等等，吉米。
It's cold outside.
外面很冷。
Put a hat on.
戴上帽子。
Okay, bye.
好的，再见。
No, wait, you'll be too cold without mittens.
不，等等，没有手套你会太冷的。
All right.
好吧。
See ya.
再见。
Hold on.
等一下。
With that wind, you're going to catch a cold.
刮着风，你会感冒的。
Wear this scarf.
戴上这条围巾。
Okay.
好的。
See you after school.
放学后见。
Oh, and earmuffs.
哦，还有耳罩。
Put these on.
戴上这些。
Here we go.
好了。
Yes, honey.
是的，亲爱的。
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
Here we go.
好了。
Yes, honey.
是的，亲爱的。
I can't breathe.
我喘不过气来了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So as you mentioned, in Chicago it's very, very cold.
所以就像你提到的，在芝加哥非常非常冷。
So I imagine you had all of these winter clothes, right?
所以我猜你所有这些冬衣都有，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And it's funny because I remember being a small child and my mother doing this to me,
而且很有趣，因为我记得小时候我妈妈也这样对我，
putting on snow pants and boots and earmuffs and hats and gloves and scarves.
给我穿上雪裤、靴子、耳罩、帽子、手套和围巾。
And all of a sudden, it's winter and I'm standing on my own.
突然之间，冬天来了，我自己站着。
And my mother's like, oh, you're getting a cold?
然后我妈妈会说：“哦，你感冒了吗？”
And I'm like, no, I'm not.
我就说：“不，我没有。”
I'm not cold.
我不冷。
So I imagine you had all of these winter clothes, right?
所以我猜你所有这些冬衣都有，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
because I remember being a small child
因为我记得小时候
and my mother doing this to me,
我妈妈就是这样对我做的，
putting on snow pants and boots and earmuffs
穿上雪裤、靴子和耳罩
and hats and gloves and scarves,
还有帽子、手套和围巾，
and all of a sudden, it's so hot inside
然后突然之间，屋里变得好热
because you're wearing everything
因为你穿得里三层外三层
and so you can't even walk like you were saying,
就像你说的，连走路都困难，
you look like a penguin walking out the door.
出门时看起来像只企鹅。
And then you get to school and you're sweating, right?
然后到了学校，你浑身是汗，对吧？
And so in school, we had to take,
所以在学校里，我们得去
we had a special room and we had to take everything off
一个专门的房间，把所有东西都脱掉
because there's snow everywhere
因为到处都是雪
and snow can be very dangerous because it melts
雪可能很危险，因为它会融化
and it turns into water.
变成水。
Okay, so I have very strong memories of all of this,
好吧，所以我对这些记忆非常深刻，
putting them on, taking them off
穿上它们，脱下它们
and just being warm all the time.
而且一直都很暖和。
Well, yeah, when it's cold
嗯，是啊，当天气冷的时候
or you live in a place with cold weather,
或者你住在寒冷的地方，
you have to have these items of clothing
你就得穿这些衣服
because otherwise you might catch a cold.
否则可能会感冒。
Exactly, so I hope that no one out there catches a cold,
没错，所以我希望没有人感冒，
but if you want some suggestions,
但如果你想要一些建议，
wear a scarf, cover your neck, that's the most important,
戴条围巾，护住脖子，那是最重要的，
your head and your scarf are the most important.
你的头和围巾是最关键的。
All right, and if you guys have any other questions
好了，如果你们还有其他问题
or comments, you can visit our website, englishpod.com
或评论，可以访问我们的网站 englishpod.com
and we'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Bye.
再见。
♪♪♪